Mae Craford

maecraford@gmail.com maecraford.github.io 650.842.0692

I am a creative spirit enabling clients deepest dreams to turn tangible. My experiences with developing effective branding, UI/UX design, prototyping, coding websites, and diverse clients will assure your safety in my capable hands.

Education

Parsons School of Design

2017-2021

BFA Communication Design

- · Graduated Summa Cum Laude- 3.7+ GPA
- Reciepient of Deans Scholarship 2017-2021

Skills

· HTML/CSS

Customer Service

UI/UX Design

Color Theory

Adobe Creative Suite

· Leadership Experience

Typography

Prototyping

• Printmaking

Sales

Teamwork

Video Editing

Experience

Sign Artist & Crew Member

Trader Joe's

03.2022 - current

Mountain View , CA

- Experience designing and creating signs of varying sizes for optimal communication to a range of customers.
- Teamwork and sales based environment.

Graphic Designer

09.2021 - current

Freelance

- Design & deliver digital content using HTML and CSS
- Spearhead complete rebranding for clients including logo design typography, website design, and packaging.
- · Developed comprehensive style guides and UI toolkits
- · Clients in fields from entertainment to biotechnology

Art Director 05.2018 - 09.2021

Montecito Seguoia Lodge

- Taught art classes on Typography, Color Theory, and Fine Arts to camp clients ages 1-100 yrs old.
- Created weekly schedules based on a diverse range of art mediums, client requests, and available materials
- Enhanced client experiences through one on one instruction and addressing concerns.

Art Teacher 09.2020 - 12.2020

Gnarly Studio

Provided 2 hr weekly lessons to 4 clients with detailed lesson plans to increase students current knowledge and artistic skills

Managed & supplied a private studio

Co-Founder 08.2016 - 12.2018

Cultured Stickers

- Small sticker company, Top Seller on Etsy
- Designed, produced, and shipped stickers for an international clientele
- Created custom orders upon request

Kings Canyon National Park, CA

Los Altos, CA

San Francisco, CA